

joanne.saad@gmail.com / www.joannesaaddesigns.com / linkedin.com/in/joannesaad

≡ SUMMARY

Leverages a background in engineering, business, and design to bring a unique perspective to solving problems. Firmly believes that empathy, collaboration, and a confidence to experiment are the foundation of intelligent design. A serial learner who enjoys participating in all facets of the design process and exploring new methods for delivering better user experiences.

Adventurous, adaptable, and insatiably curious gym bunny living in London, Uk.

EDUCATION

UX Designer Certificate

Feb 2019 - Jun 2020

CareerFoundry

Remote

Intensive training program specializing in UX processes and methodologies. Including: user research, journeys, personas, flows, testing, IA, and visual design fundamentals.

MBA (Hon.)

Nov 2014 - Dec 2015

IE Business School

Madrid, Spain

Specialized in Finance; Cumulative GPA: 3.5; Top 10% of graduate class; Dean's List.

Post-Baccalaureate Business

Certificate

Jan 2013 - Jul 2013

Columbia University

New York, USA

Finance focus; Cumulative GPA: 4.165

BSc. (Hon.) Civil Engineering Aug 2005 - May 2009

Tufts University

Medford, USA

Cumulative GPA: 3.91; Summa Cum Laude; Dean's List.

X SKILLS & TOOLS

Design

User Surveys and Interviews Competitive Analysis

Wireframing

Prototyping

Sketching and Storyboarding

Personas and Scenario Development

User Flows

Information Architecture

User Testing and Data Analysis

Project Management

Visual and Graphic Design

Branding

Copywriting

Responsive Design

Technical

Illustrator; Photoshop; InDesign; AdobeXD; AfterEffects; Sketch; InVision; Balsamiq; Prott; MS Office/G Suite; AutoDesk; HTML5; CSS3; JavaScript; Python; VBA; MATLAB

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer

Jul 2013 - Present

Freelance

Remote

- ➤ Participate in client correspondence to determine the scope of various design projects;
- > Conceptualize, create and present design solutions and assets for a variety of clients for web, mobile, and print projects;
- Conduct user research to inform strategic decisions used in crafting design solutions;
- Communicate with stakeholders to ensure business objectives are met

Business Development Manager

Jan 2016 - Present

Soma Bay Tourism Investment

Cairo, Egypt

- > Developed the creation and implemeentation of a Business Continuity Plan;
- > Review of operating and financial performance of 5 Hotels;
- Developed a financial restructuring plan, including negotiating a solution to delinquent debt at 2 hotels;
- > Develop a program to optimise the benefits associated with foreign currency revenues;
- Responsible for building and maintaining effective business relationships to attract and retain profitable business;
- Manage money-market financial investments and budget forecasts;
- > Evaluate new investment opportunities;
- Assist in Corporate Management including BOD and OGM representation.

Structural Engineer

Jul 2010 - Dec 2012

Fluid Structures

London, UK

- ➤ Responsible for 40+ projects from earliest conceptual stage through to detailed design, ranging from larger education and retail (up to £10m) to residential and specialist design (up to £5m);
- Prepared Fee Proposals, design calculations and analyses, detailed structural drawings, Structural Specifications,
- > Feasibility Reports, and Structural Planning Reports;
- ➤ Liaised with Clients, Architects, consulting teams, Planning Authority etc., and attended regular design team meetings to discuss progress-to-date and establish future works;
- Attended site to inspect and log opening-up works, supervise construction, and respond to "Requests For Information";
- Responsible for Project Management and Financing, including issuing monthly invoices and monitoring bad debts;
- Led a team of three graduates to deliver projects on tight deadlines to RIBA Stage C, D & E;
- Completed research reports on topics such as Drainage Design, The Use of Acrylic as a Structural Material, Wind Design
- Analysis, and The Design of Low-Energy Buildings for 21st Century;
- > Responsible for creating presentations to pitch new jobs.

* ACTIVITIES

orosts

UX Design Meetup Coordinator; Hiking (Climbed Kilimanjaro; Camino de Santiago de Compostella Pilgrimage - 850km); Bikram yoga; Pilates; HIIT Training; Traveling; Learning

Languages

English; French; Arabic (conversational)